pa--pah khan chúi-gû
Papa leads the water buffalo
kiâⁿ kòe chhân-hōaⁿ piⁿ
Walking past the ridges of the rice paddy
siūⁿ tio̍h siáⁿ-mi̍h
Thinking of something
oa̍t-thâu tùi gún
He turns his head toward me
chhiò kah chhùi hi-hi
Smiling with a broad grin
chhiah-chhiah-chhiah chhiah-chhiah-chhiah
(Splash, splash, splash - sound of the waterwheel)
chòe chi̍t-ê lông-ka lú-jî
Being a daughter of a farming family
múi-ji̍t ta̍h chúi-chhia
Treading the waterwheel every day
eh~ iu-goân iā sî-siông chhiùⁿ koa-si
Eh~ I still often sing songs
an-ùi sim khang-hi
To comfort the emptiness in my heart
pe lâi iū pe khì
Flying back and forth
chi̍t-tùi pe̍h-lēng-si
A pair of white egrets
ín gún su-liām
Triggering my longing
sim-ài ko--koh
For my beloved
lân-bōng ê chêng-bī
The unforgettable feeling of love
chhiah-chhiah-chhiah chhiah-chhiah-chhiah
(Splash, splash, splash - sound of the waterwheel)
pang-bâng tio̍h nî-lāu pa--pah
Helping my elderly papa
múi-ji̍t ta̍h chúi-chhia
Treading the waterwheel every day
eh~ chiàu sim-goān tiàm-chāi i sin-piⁿ
Eh~ wishing to be by his side as I desire
tio̍h-ài tán hô-sî
How long must I wait?
ūi-tio̍h i ha̍k-gia̍p
For the sake of his studies
tiàm-chāi sió siâⁿ-chhī
He lives in a small city
hit-ji̍t phoe-sìn
The letter from that day
iā-sī kiò gún
Also told me
jím-nāi sim hi-bî
To endure the loneliness in my heart
chhiah-chhiah-chhiah chhiah-chhiah-chhiah
(Splash, splash, splash - sound of the waterwheel)
kî-thāi tio̍h khoài-lo̍k chhun-thiⁿ
Looking forward to a happy spring
múi-ji̍t ta̍h chúi-chhia
Treading the waterwheel every day
eh~ nā thiaⁿ kìⁿ o͘-chhiu teh kiò-thî
Eh~ if I hear the black drongo calling
tōa-khùi thò͘ bōe-lī
I cannot stop sighing deeply