The Frog Prince.
A big shout out to Ellie and Alexis
for requesting today's story.
Once upon a time in a kingdom deep in the forest,
there lived a young princess.
She was fair and lovely,
with hair like sunlight and eyes like the clear sky.
Her favorite treasure was a golden ball,
which she loved to toss into the air and catch
over and over, especially near the cool well
in the far end of the palace garden.
Day after day she tossed it high into the air,
laughing as it glittered in the sunlight.
One warm afternoon as she played,
the ball slipped from her hands,
bounced upon the edge of the well,
and fell with a splash into the water below.
The well was deep,
and no matter how she leaned she could not see its bottom.
Oh my beautiful golden ball.
If only I could have you back again,
I would give anything, anything in the world.
Why do you weep so, Princess?
It is my golden ball, it has fallen into the well,
and I shall never see it again.
I can fetch it for you,
but what will you give me in return?
Oh dear frog, I will give you jewels and pearls,
and even the golden crown I wear.
I have no need for your riches.
But if you will promise to let me be your companion,
to sit beside you at table,
to eat from your plate, to drink from your cup,
and to sleep upon your bed,
then I will dive down and bring back your ball.
The princess shuddered at the thought.
A slimy frog at my table? On my pillow? Never!
Yet she wished so dearly for her toy that she said quickly:
Yes, yes.
I promise whatever you ask.
But the princess had no thought of keeping her word.
At once the frog plunged beneath the water.
Moments later he returned, pushing the golden ball up.
The princess snatched it joyfully.
Without another thought, she ran back to the palace.
Wait Princess! Take me with you,
as you promised!
My ball, my lovely ball.
That night as the royal family sat down to supper,
a knock sounded at the Great Hall door.
The princess went to open it,
and there sitting upon the step was the frog.
Princess open the door!
Do you not remember your promise by the well?
Let me sit beside you and eat from your plate.
The princess turned pale
and slammed the door shut.
What troubles you my daughter?
There is a frog outside.
He says that I promised that he'd eat with me,
but I do not want him here.
A princess must keep her word, even to a frog.
Bring him in.
Reluctantly the princess opened the door.
The frog hopped across the floor up to the table and said:
Lift me up beside you.
Against her will she obeyed.
He sat next to her and demanded:
"Now push your plate closer that I may eat as you do."
She pushed the plate and the frog ate heartily from her food.
He drank from her goblet and left wet prints on the linen.
The princess was disgusted,
but the king only nodded gravely, watching her honor her promise.
I am weary now.
Take me to your chamber that I may sleep upon your bed.
Father must I truly allow this creature to sleep near me?
A princess must keep her word, even to a frog.
So with heavy heart she carried the frog upstairs,
placed him upon a cushion by her bedside and lay down.
I am lonely down here.
Kiss me goodnight princess, as you would a dear companion.
The princess trembled with horror. Kiss a frog? Never!
Yet her father's words rang in her ears: a promise must be kept.
She squeezed her eyes shut, bent quickly,
and pressed her lips to his cold damp skin.
In that instant the frog was gone.
And in his place stood a young prince,
his eyes kind and shining.
Who are you?
I was a prince enchanted by a wicked witch.
Only when a princess kept her word and kissed me
could the spell be broken.
You have set me free.
Will you come with me to my kingdom and be my queen?
Yes I will.
The next day a carriage arrived sent from the prince's kingdom.
Driving it was his loyal servant Iron Heinrich,
whose heart had been bound with three iron bands
for fear it would break while his master lived under the curse.
Go well my child and always remember to honor your word.
Happily the princess left her father's kingdom behind.
What was that sound?
It is Heinrich. His heart is so full of joy
that the iron bands around it are breaking.
The prince and princess rode away together to his kingdom,
where they were married and lived happily ever after.